A Guide to the Trust for Mutual Understanding records FA412
Rockefeller Archive Center
Trust for Mutual Understanding records
1963, 1965, 1968, 1970, 1972, 1974-1976, 1978-2012
Rockefeller Archive Center
Trust for Mutual Understanding
FA412
52.69 Cubic Feet 138 document boxes, 2 3" x 5" card boxes
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Trust for Mutual Understanding records were donated to the Rockefeller Archive Center by Richard Lanier (TMU President), January 2008.
Conditions Governing Access
Records ten years old or older are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Biographical / Historical
The Trust for Mutual Understanding was established in 1984 by an anonymous American philanthropist as a private, grantmaking organization dedicated to promoting improved communication, closer cooperation, and greater respect between the people of the United States, the Soviet Union, and other countries in Eastern and Central Europe. TMU's program reflects her conviction that grantmaking can make a contribution to that process by supporting international face-to-face contact and professional interaction. TMU's mission has been shaped by the belief that creative international collaboration encourages global harmony.
TMU continues to support East-West exchanges in the arts and environment, reflecting the founder's appreciation of the importance of culture and ecology in people's lives. Before 1985, there was relatively little American funding for such activities, and what support there was—mainly governmental—was often restricted by political considerations. It remains TMU's goal to enable talented people to come together from different countries to freely share ideas and stimulate creativity in a nonpolitical context.
Mission: The Trust for Mutual Understanding awards grants to American nonprofit organizations to support direct exchange in the arts and the environment between professionals from the United States and TMU's geographic region: the Baltic States; Central Asia; Central, East, Southeast Europe; Mongolia; and Russia.
Priority consideration is given to projects that involve direct, in-depth professional interaction, with the potential for sustained collaboration; that show evidence of professional accomplishment and innovation; and/or that respond to social contexts and engage local communities.
(www.tmuny.org)
Scope and Contents
This collection contains reports, correspondence, audiovisual materials (videos, CDs, photographs and negatives), and publications. The collection contains materials about Eastern European Art organizations and the environmental groups which were promoted through grants made by the Trust for Mutual Understanding. Grants were made directly to the Eastern European institutions or American institutions who were working in collaboration with an Eastern European organization.
Arrangement
Arranged in 5 series by file type.
- Administrative and Financial, 1983-1996; 1; 4.18 Cubic Feet 11 letter document boxes
  Scope and Contents
  Materials in Series 1 contain: minutes, correspondence, chronological files, and other materials pertaining to the administratiion of TMU and Asian Cultural Council (ACC)
  - Administrative Expenses, 1985-1988, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Administrative Expenses Payments, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alaska Performing Artists for Peace, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Repertory Theatre and Russian-American Performing Arts Center, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Americas Watch, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Appropriations and Payments, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Asian Cultural Council (ACC), 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Asian Cultural Council (ACC) Annual Reports and Brochure, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Asian Cultural Council (ACC) Chronological Files, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 9-11)
  - Asian Cultural Council (ACC) Chronological Files, 1994-1996 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting, 1984-1989 (Box 2, Folder 13-21)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting, 1989-1991 (Box 3, Folder 22-29)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Board of Trustees, Minutes, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Budgets, 1986-1987, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 32-34)
  - Chronological Files, 1988-1991 (Box 4, Folder 35-37)
  - Chronological FIles, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 38-43)
  - Chronological Files, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 44-48)
  - Chronological Files, 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 49-52)
  - Committee on American Museums and Miscellaneous, 1985-1991, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 53-54)
  - E-Mail Correspondence, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Financial Procedures, 1985-1986, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Grant Appropriations, 1987-1989, 1992-1996 (Box 8, Folder 57-61)
  - Grant Declinations, 1987-1988, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Grant Information, 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - Grant Summaries, 1992, 1994-1997 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Harvard University, Russian Research Center, 1985, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - IRS Dcouments, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Lanier, Richard S., Boston Trip, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - Lanier, Richard S., Eastern Europe Trip, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - Lanier, Richard S., Hong Kong Trips, 1986-1989 (Box 9, Folder 69)
  - Lanier, Richard S., Meetings and Invitations, Declinations, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - Lanier, Richard S., Washington and Gettysburg Trip, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 71)
  - Lanier, Richard S., Washington, D. C., Festival of Indonesia, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 72)
  - Indo-US Subcommission, 1985-1987 (Box 9, Folder 73)
  - The Institute for Soviet-American Relations, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 74)
  - The International Foundation for the Survival and Development of Humanity, 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 75)
  - McLean, Marcia, 1986-1992 (Box 9, Folder 76-77)
  - New York Foundation on the Arts, Inc., 1991 (Box 9, Folder 78)
  - Organizational Addresses and Contacts, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 79)
  - People and Resumes, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 80)
  - Policy, Procedure, and Legal, 1987-1988 (Box 10, Folder 81)
  - Quarterly Cash Requirements, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - Request for Materials, 1985-1987 (Box 10, Folder 83)
  - Research Material, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 84)
  - Sandra Ferry Trust, 1983-1986, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 85)
  - Soviet Delegation, Meeting, 1987-1988 (Box 10, Folder 86)
  - Status Reports and Meetings, 1985-1987 (Box 10, Folder 87)
  - The Talking Band, 1986-1990 (Box 10, Folder 88)
  - TAWA/Soviet Arts Exchange, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 89)
  - Thirty Years of U.S.-Soviet Exchange, Report, 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 90)
  - Trust Declaration, 1984 May 3, 1984, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 91)
  - Trust Expenses, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 92)
  - Trust Review, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 93)
  - Trustees and Sandra Ferry, Photograph (Box 10, Folder 94)
  - University Art Museums, University of California, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 95)
  - Washington-Moscow Art Exchange, 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 96)
  - Wheaton College, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 97)
  - World Fisheries Congress, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 98)
- Paulette Rosselet Walther (PRW)/JDR 3rd Fund, 1963, 1965, 1968, 1972, 1974, 1976, 1978-1997; 2; 3.32 Cubic Feet 8 letter document boxes and 2 card file boxes
  Biographical / Historical
  After joining the Rockefeller Brothers Fund in 1972, she moved to the Rockefeller philanthropic office where she helped to coordinate the charitable giving of a number of family members. For the past 12 years, she served as program associate at the Trust for Mutual Understanding, bringing to her work a professional commitment and a striving for excellence matched only by her personal warmth and her wonderful sensitivity. Her dedication, enthusiasm and genuine caring for others earned her the admiration and respect of everyone involved in the trust's efforts to encourage greater understanding between the United States and the countries of East and Central Europe. Died 21 November 1997 (New York Times, Section D, pg 23, 25 November 1997)
  - JDR 3rd's Will and Memorandum of 1978 July 10 to the Executors, 1976, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 99)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, 1980-1981, 1984, 1986-1989 (Box 11, Folder 100)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, Administrative Costs, 1986-1992 (Box 11, Folder 101)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, American Soccer Project, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 102)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, Asian Cultural Council (ACC), Indo-US Subcommission on Education and Culture, 1987-1991 (Box 11, Folder 103)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, The Asia Society, 1976, 1983-1984, 1987, 1989-1990 (Box 11, Folder 104-105)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, Bernard Bailyn, 1978, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 106)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, Balance Sheet and Grant Correspondence, 1987-1988, 1991-1992 (Box 11, Folder 107)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, Board of Trustees, Meeting, 1976, 1978-1981, 1985-1990, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 108-115)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, By-Laws, 1963, 1968, 1972, 1974, 1978-1979, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 116)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, Cambridge College, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 117)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, Changing Schools Through the Arts, How to Build on the Power of an Idea, Jane Remer, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 118)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, Council on Foundations, 1982-1991 (Box 12, Folder 119)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, Declinations, 1989-1991 (Box 13, Folder 120)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, Financials, 1988-1991 (Box 13, Folder 121)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, Foundation Center, 1990-1991 (Box 13, Folder 122)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, Grant Distributions, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 123)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, Hampshire College, 1988-1990 (Box 13, Folder 124)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, The International Foundation for the Survival and Development of Humanity, 1988-1990 (Box 13, Folder 125)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, Legal, 1987-1988, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 126)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, Mental Illness Counseling Center, 1987-1989 (Box 13, Folder 127)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, Miscellaneous, 1991, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 128)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, National Charities Information Bureau, 1987-1988, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 129)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, New York regional Association of Grant Makers, 1982-1990, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 130)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, Peabody, Art of Asmat, 1988-1990 (Box 13, Folder 131)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, Planned Parenthood of New York City, 1988-1989 (Box 13, Folder 132)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, Planned Parenthood of Westchester/Rockland, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 133)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, Population Council, 1987-1990 (Box 13, Folder 134)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, Rockefeller University, JDR 150th Anniversary Conference, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 135)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, Rutgers University, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 136)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, Staff Handbook, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 137)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, Summary of Contributions, 1982, 1987-1992 (Box 14, Folder 138)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, The Synergos Institute, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 139)
  - American Association of Museums (AAM), 1990, 1992-1994 (Box 14, Folder 140-141)
  - Articles and Letters, 1988, 1993-1995 (Box 14, Folder 142)
  - ArtsLink, 1991, 1994-1997 (Box 14, Folder 143)
  - ArtsLink Conference, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 144)
  - Center for Marine Conservation, 1986-1992 (Box 14, Folder 145-146)
  - Center for Marine Conservation, 1986-1992 (Box 15, Folder 147)
  - Center for Strategic & International Studies, 1993-1994 (Box 15, Folder 148)
  - Chautauqua Conference, US-Soviet Relations, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 149)
  - College Art Association, 1995-1996 (Box 15, Folder 150)
  - Correspondence, 1985 June-1986 December (Box 15, Folder 151)
  - Correspondence, Organizations, 1988, 1990-1993 (Box 15, Folder 152-154)
  - Earthwatch, 1981, 1988, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 155)
  - Eastern Europe Trip, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 156)
  - Eastern Europe Trip, 1994-1997 (Box 16, Folder 157-158)
  - Environmental Grantmakers Association, 1992-1996 (Box 16, Folder 159-160)
  - Foundation Directories, 1992-1994, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 161)
  - Grants Appropriated, 1985, 1991-1992, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 162)
  - Grant Checks, 1992-1993 (Box 16, Folder 163)
  - Grant Related Expenses, 1995-1996 (Box 16, Folder 164)
  - Lower East Side Tenement Museum, 1990-1991 (Box 16, Folder 165)
  - Memberships, 1991-1996 (Box 16, Folder 166-167)
  - Michael Clark Rockefeller Memorial Fellowship, 1990-1991 (Box 17, Folder 168)
  - Mid-America Arts Alliance, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 169)
  - Miscellaneous, 1991-1992, 1994-1997 (Box 17, Folder 170)
  - Nonprofit Coordinating Committee on New York (NPCC), 1993-1994 (Box 17, Folder 172)
  - PACT (Private Agencies Collaborating Together), 1990 (Box 17, Folder 173)
  - Peace Child, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 174)
  - Prague and Budapest, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 175)
  - Pending Requests, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 176)
  - Soviet Foundations, Miscellaneous, 1989-1991 (Box 17, Folder 177)
  - Subscriptions, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 178)
  - The Synergos Institute, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 179)
  - Trip Notebooks, 1996-1997 (Box 17, Folder 180-181)
  - The University of Mississippi, 1989-1990 (Box 17, Folder 182)
  - White Earth Land Recovery Project, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 183)
  - Yale University, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 184)
  - JDR 3rd Fund, Mailing List for Elizabeth McCormack (Box 139)
  - Walther, Paulette Rosselet, Rolodex (Box 140)
- Grants, 1970, 1975, 1978, 1982, 1987-2012; 3; 45.95 Cubic Feet 121 letter document boxes
  This series contains materials pertaining to the grants the TMU awarded to American non-profit organizations. Materials include grant applications, newspaper and magazine articles, flyers, brochures and publications, photographs, and digital materials.
  - 3-Legged Dog Media, DF-0803, 2006-2008 (Box 18, Folder 185)
  - 3-Legged Dog Media, DF-0803, Photos (Box 18, Folder 185)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
  - 18th Street Arts Center, B-0540, 2005-2008 (Box 18, Folder 186)
  - 18th Street Arts Center, DF-0427, DF-0507, 2004-2006 (Box 18, Folder 187)
  - 18th Street Arts Center, Miscellaneous, B-0507, 2004, 2008 (Box 18, Folder 188-189)
  - 18th Street Arts Center, B-0650, 2006-2007 (Box 18, Folder 190)
  - 18th Street Arts Center, B-0750, 2007-2009 (Box 18, Folder 191)
  - 18th Street Arts Center, DF-0740, 2007-2009 (Box 18, Folder 192)
  - 18th Street Arts Center, B-0804, 2008-2009 (Box 19, Folder 193)
  - 59E59 Theaters, B-0805, 2008-2009 (Box 19, Folder 194-195)
  - 59E59 Theaters, B-0805, "Made In Poland" Festival, Images (Box 19, Folder 194)
  - 59E59 Theaters, B-0805, Theatre of the Eighth Day, Meeting with the Polish Daily News Readers (Box 19, Folder 194)
  - 10,000 Years Institute, B-0332, 2002-2004, 2006 (Box 19, Folder 196)
  - A.I.R. Gallery, DF-0645, 2006-2008 (Box 19, Folder 197)
  - A.I.R. Gallery, DF-0645, A.I.R. Grant, Facelift Exhibit, 2007 (Box 19, Folder 197)
  - Academy of Natural Sciences, B-0225, 2001-2003, 2005-2006 (Box 19, Folder 198)
  - Academy of Natural Sciences, EC-0602, 2002, 2004-2008 (Box 19, Folder 199)
  - Academy of Natural Sciences, EC-0602, Houggal GEF Video, 2006 January 29 (Box 19, Folder 199)
  - Academy of Natural Sciences, Miscellaneous, EC-0602, 2006-2007 (Box 19, Folder 200)
  - Academy of Natural Sciences, EC-0807, 2007-2009 (Box 20, Folder 201)
  - Accinosco Company, B-0806, 2008-2009 (Box 20, Folder 202)
  - Accinosco Company, B-0806, Accinosco Tour, Images, 2008 (Box 20, Folder 202)
  - The Acting Company, B-0423, 2004, 2007-2008 (Box 20, Folder 203)
  - The Advance Project, DF-0323 (Cancelled), 2003 (Box 20, Folder 204)
  - Aid to Artisans, B-0406, 2004-2005, 2007 (Box 20, Folder 205)
  - Aid to Artisans, B-0406, Georgian Exhibit (Box 20, Folder 205)
  - Alarm Will Sound, B-0751, 2007-2009 (Box 20, Folder 206)
  - Alaska Marine Conservation Council, DF-0216, 2002-2003, 2006 (Box 20, Folder 207)
  - Alexandra Beller Dances, B-0851, 1996, 2003, 2006-2009 (Box 20, Folder 208)
  - Alliance for Nuclear Accountability, B-0570, 2005-2006, 2008 (Box 20, Folder 209)
  - Alliance to Save Energy, B-01107, 2001-2003, 2006-2007 (Box 20, Folder 210)
  - Alonzo King's LINES Ballet, B-0183, 2000-2003, 2006-2007 (Box 20, Folder 211)
  - Altai Assistance Project, B-0526, 2005, 2007 (Box 20, Folder 212)
  - Altai Assistance Project, B-0526, TMU Pictures, 5/12, 2011:012:001 (Box 20, Folder 212)
  - Altai Assistance Project, B-0638, 2006-2007 (Box 21, Folder 213)
  - Altai Assistance Project, B-0740, 2005-2008 (Box 21, Folder 214)
  - Altai Assistance Project, B-0740, Altai Assistance Project, 2007 December 6 (Box 21, Folder 214)
  - Altai Assistance Project, B-0740 (Box 21, Folder 214)
  - Altai Assistance Project, Miscellaneous (Adirondack Sustainable Communities), B-0740, 2007-2008 (Box 21, Folder 215)
  - Altai Assistance Project, Miscellaneous (Adirondack Sustainable Communities), B-0740, Visions of the Blue Valley, 2015:015:004
  - Altai Assistance Project, B0839, 2005, 2008, 2010, 2012 (Box 21, Folder 216)
  - America-Bosnia Cultural Foundation, EC-0500, 2004-2005, 2008 (Box 21, Folder 217)
  - America-Bosnia Cultural Foundation, Miscellaneous, Sasha Toperich, EC-0500, 2002 (Box 21, Folder 218)
  - American Academy in Rome, B-0752, 2007-2008 (Box 21, Folder 219)
  - American Artists Abroad, DF-0433, 2004-2007, 2009 (Box 21, Folder 220)
  - American Artists Abroad, DF-0533, 2005, 2007-2009 (Box 21, Folder 221)
  - American Association of Museums, B-0214, 2002-2003, 2006 (Box 21, Folder 222)
  - American Association of Museums, B-0344, 2003-2007 (Box 21, Folder 223)
  - American Councils for International Exchange, DF-0233, 2002-2003, 2006 (Box 21, Folder 224)
  - American Dance Festival, B-0115, 2001, 2003 (Box 21, Folder 225)
  - American Dance Festival, EC-0201, 1999, 2001-2003 (Box 21, Folder 226)
  - American Dance Festival, B-0345, 2002-2004 (Box 21, Folder 227)
  - American Dance Festival, DF-0311, 2002-2003 (Box 22, Folder 228)
  - American Dance Festival, B-0447, 2004-2005, 2007 (Box 22, Folder 229)
  - American Dance Festival, EC-0403, 2003-2006 (Box 22, Folder 230)
  - American Dance Festival, EC-0403, Photos from ADF Mongolia, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 230)
  - American Dance Festival, B-0541, 2004-2007 (Box 22, Folder 231)
  - American Dance Festival, B-0541, Provincial Dances Theatre, 2006 (Box 22, Folder 231)
  - American Dance Festival, B-0541, ADF/Mongolia, 2006 (Box 22, Folder 231)
  - American Dance Festival, B-0541, ADF Images, 2006 (Box 22, Folder 231)
  - American Dance Festival, B-0651, 2006-2008; 2011:012:062; CD (Box 22, Folder 232)
  - American Dance Festival, B-0651, Select Photos, Chelyabinsk Contemporary Dance Theatre, Iguan Dance Theatre, Vladimir Golubev, 2007 (Box 22, Folder 232)
  - American Dance Festival, DF-0638, 2006-2007 (Box 22, Folder 233)
  - American Dance Festival, B-0753, 2007-2009 (Box 22, Folder 234)
  - American Dance Festival, B-0753, 2008 Russian ICR's, Photos by American Dance Festival, Sara D. Davis (Box 22, Folder 234)
  - American Dance Festival, Miscellaneous, B-0753, 2008 (Box 22, Folder 235)
  - American Dance Festival, Miscellaneous, B-0753, ADF's 2008 Final Report to the Trust for Mutual Understanding, Selected Photos (Box 22, Folder 235)
  - American Dance Festival, B-0852, 1992, 2006, 2008-2009 (Box 22, Folder 236)
  - American Dance Festival, B-0852, ICR Photos, 2009 (Box 22, Folder 236)
  - American Dance Festival, B-0852, International Choreographers Showing, From Jodee Nimerichter with Final Report, 2009 July 19 (Box 22, Folder 236)
  - American Forests, Trees for Tigers, B-0163, 2001-2002, 2006 (Box 22, Folder 237)
  - American Friends of the Russian Country Estate, A-FORCE, DF-0119, 2001-2002 (Box 22, Folder 238)
  - American Friends of the Russian Country Estate, DF-0222, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 239)
  - American Friends of the State Hermitage Museum, B-0234, 2002-2003, 2006 (Box 22, Folder 240)
  - American Friends of the State Hermitage Museum, DF-0324, 2003, 2006 (Box 22, Folder 241)
  - The American Friends of the Tretyakov Gallery, DF-0605, 2004-2006 (Box 22, Folder 242)
  - American Museum of the Moving Image, B-01110, 2001-2003, 2006-2007 (Box 22, Folder 243)
  - American Museum of Natural History, DF-0102, 2001-2004 (Box 22, Folder 244)
  - American Museum of Natural History, DF-0434, 2004-2005 (Box 22, Folder 245)
  - American Museum of Natural History, DF-0535, 2005-2006 (Box 23, Folder 246)
  - American Museum of Natural History, Miscellaneous, DF-0535, 1997, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 247)
  - American Philosophical Society, B-0305, 2001-2004, 2006-2007 (Box 23, Folder 248)
  - American Philosophical Society, B-0305, Digital Image of Sue Ann Prince in Russia (Box 22, Folder 248)
  - American Philosophical Society, DF-0338, 2003-2007 (Box 23, Folder 249)
  - American Repertory Theatre, DF-0106, 2001-2003 (Box 23, Folder 250)
  - American Repertory Theater, B-0346, B-0404, B-0501, 2003-2007; B-0501 (Box 23, Folder 251)
  - American Repertory Theater, Miscellaneous, B-0346, B-0404, B-0501, 2002 (Box 23, Folder 252)
  - American Repertory Theatre, B-0652, B-0703, 2006-2009 (Box 23, Folder 253)
  - American Repertory Theater, DF-0634 (Cancelled), 2006 (Box 23, Folder 254)
  - American Repertory Theatre, B-0853, 2008-2009 (Box 23, Folder 255)
  - American Russian Young Artists Orchestra (ARYO), B-0184, 2001-2002, 2006 (Box 23, Folder 256)
  - American Russian Young Artists Orchestra (ARYO), B-0275, 2002-2006 (Box 23, Folder 257)
  - American Russian Young Artists Orchestra (ARYO), B-0505, 2004-2005, 2008 (Box 24, Folder 258)
  - American Russian Young Artists Orchestra (ARYO), Miscellaneous, B-0505, 2004 (Box 24, Folder 259)
  - American Russian Young Artists Orchestra (Amirus), EC-0700, 2005-2007, 2009 (Box 24, Folder 260)
  - American Visionary Art Museum, B-0276 (Cancelled), 1996, 2001-2003 (Box 24, Folder 261)
  - American-Russian Cultural Cooperation Foundation, B-0347, 2003-2005 (Box 24, Folder 262)
  - American-Russian Cultural Cooperation Foundation, DF-0814, 2007-2009 (Box 24, Folder 263)
  - American-Russian Cultural Cooperation Foundation, Miscellaneous, DF-0814, 2008 (Box 24, Folder 264)
  - America's River Communities, DF-0529, 2005-2006 (Box 24, Folder 265)
  - America's River Communities, DF-0641, 2006, 2008 (Box 24, Folder 266)
  - Apexart (Laznia Centre for Contemporary Art), EC-0104, 2001-2004 (Box 24, Folder 267)
  - Apexart, Miscellaneous, EC-0104, 2002, 2005 (Box 24, Folder 268)
  - Apexart C.P., EC-0325, 2002-2004, 2006-2009 (Box 24, Folder 269)
  - Apexart, DF-0538, 2000, 2003-2006 (Box 25, Folder 270)
  - ApexArt, DF-0538, Sweet Taboos: A Mini Tarana Biennial in New York, 2006 May 24-July 1 (Box 25, Folder 270)
  - Apexart, DF-0710, 2006-2007 (Box 25, Folder 271)
  - Apexart, DF-0732, 2007 (Box 25, Folder 272)
  - Apexart, DF-0732, TMU - Sponsored Events (Box 25, Folder 272)
  - Apexart, DF-0732, Apexart "Stalking with Stories", 2007 September 19-November 3 (Box 25, Folder 272)
  - Apexart, DF-0833, 2005, 2008-2009 (Box 25, Folder 273)
  - APT Pittsburgh, B-0116, 2000-2002, 2006 (Box 25, Folder 274)
  - APT Pittsburgh, Miscellaneous, B-0116, 2001 (Box 25, Folder 275)
  - Arcady Music Society, B-0185, 1993, 2000-2003 (Box 25, Folder 276)
  - Arden2 Society, B-0506, 2004-2006 (Box 25, Folder 277)
  - Arden2 Society, B-0854, 2007-2009 (Box 25, Folder 278)
  - Arden2 Society, B-0854, US Artist Initiative, Grotowski Year, Poland, 2009 (Box 25, Folder 278)
  - Arena Dances, DF-0514, 1197, 2000, 2002, 2004-2006 (Box 25, Folder 279)
  - Arena Dances, DF-0800, 2006-2008 (Box 25, Folder 280)
  - Arena Dances, DF-0800, Arena Dances (Box 25, Folder 280)